

# Ray Berry

## **SUMMARY - Project Manager**

I am an experienced IT professional with a background in financial, retail and automotive industries delivering IT projects using Agile and Waterfall techniques for both offshore and onshore teams. I am a qualified Scrum Master (PSM1). I have a good understanding of the mobile App development process with experience of designing and developing Apple Apps.



rayberryrb@gmail.com



07951 010595



App Portfolio



Bourne, Nr Peterborough

in linkedin.com/in/rav-berry

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Agile Scrum Master PSM1 Project Management Jira Confluence Sprint planning
- UI/UX Design Wireframes Mock-ups Human Interface Guidelines
- iOS Developer Swift 5 Xcode 10 Github Firebase CoreData Realm CoreML ARKit
- Rest API JSON Cocoapods Carthage Alamofire MVC Tableviews Collection Views SpriteKit
- VideoStreaming(HLS)
  User Authentication (FaceID, TouchID)
- TDD XCTest
- ERP process integration B2B EDI XML AS2

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

iOS Developer Freelance 10/2017 - Present Bourne, UK

- Good knowledge of Swift 5 and Xcode 10.
- Developed the following Apps:
  - o FileIT Inventory Management to track inventory to assist with home insurance or moving house. Uses Core Data, User Authentication and Core Graphics Animation.
  - Weather using Rest APIs, JSON and GPS location data to retrieve weather data.
  - Augmented Reality Tape measure using ARkit and Scenekit to measure 3D objects.
  - Video Streaming using HLS (Http Live Streaming) to showcase apps that I have developed.
- UI/UX Design experience of creating wireframes and mock-ups.
- Use of XCtest for Test Driven Development (TDD).

## **Development Manager**

BGL Group Ltd

2012 - 10/2017

Peterborough UK

- Successfully managed a scrum team delivering internal financial services projects.
- Scrum Master for the 'WatchMen' team. Knowledge and use of Scrum Agile processes including: sprint planning; daily stand-ups; two week sprint cycles; sprint reviews and retrospectives.
- Qualified Professional Scrum Master with PSM1 certification.
- Use of Scrum Poker, Three Amigos, Scrum of Scrums and burn down charts.
- Understanding and use of Kanban boards.
- Use of pair programming within the team.
- Understanding and using the Atlassian tools: Jira and Confluence (CRM) to manage sprints, user stories and updating the sprint and product backlog. Understanding and use of JQL (Jira query language).
- Use of Slack and Trello.

#### **NEU IS Supply Services Lead**

Reckitt Benckiser

2010 - 2012

Hull, UK

- Managing a cross-section of IT projects ranging from senior management reporting, cost reduction exercises, automation of business interfaces between JDE and Siebel; Manugistics and EDI packages.
- The project management encompassed resource allocation, budget control, prioritisation, risk analysis, project delivery and post implementation reviews.

#### **European IS Supply Services Lead**

Reckitt Benckiser

2006 - 2009

Hull, UK

• Project managing teams as well as working with external off-shore support from Bangalore, India to ensure implementation of a demand planning tool (Manugistics 7.2) across sixteen countries in Europe. Managing project budget for Europe for over £1m for Manugistics rollouts.

#### **EDI Senior Business Analyst**

Reckitt Benckiser

2003 - 2006

Hull, UK

- I was responsible for EDI within Europe for RB. I was responsible for a team of five supporting the EDI infrastructure within seventeen countries across Europe.
- Consultancy role on EDI interface design and development into JD Edwards.
- Good EDI mapping experience using Inovis TLI series visual mapper. Mapping in TRADACOM, EDIFACT, ANSI X12 and EANCOM subsets i.e HANCOM. Written code in RPG for interface routines.

## **Freelance EDI Consultant**

Freelance

1998 - 2003

Chiswick/Slough, UK

• EDI integration specialist in BPCS and JD Edwards using Harbinger /Inovis Trusted Link I series EDI interfacing products and RPG.

### **EDUCATION**

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Cambridge College of Arts and Technology (1989) HND in Software Engineering		<ul><li>Swift</li><li>RPG</li></ul>
		<ul><li>COBOL</li></ul>
Knowsley Tertiary College	(1987)	BASIC
OND in Computer Studies		<ul><li>C (basic understanding)</li></ul>
Higherside Comprehensive School	(1985)	GitHub Repository
,	,	<u> </u>
7 O' levels including Maths, English and Computer Studies		

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

2014 - Round Table President (Bourne)

2014 - Burghley Rat Race 20 Mile Assault course

2008 - Round Table Chairman (Bourne)

2006 - London Marathon

2005 - BUPA North Half Marathon